U.S. Agency for International Development Records, Programs, and Itineraries 5384
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Agency for International Development Records, Programs, and Itineraries
1960-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Agency for International Development
5384
5.33 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of the program and itinerary for each of the various AID sponsored training programs carried out in the U.S. and other countries.
5622229
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 17, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
U. S. Agency for International Development
On September 4, 1961 the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 vas signed into law. On November 4, 1961 the Agency for International Development was set up in the Department of State to succeed the International Cooperation Administration. The main objective of AID was to combine the various foreign assistance programs into one program which would assist the underdeveloped countries in maintaining their independence by making them self-supporting nations. The Development Loan Fund, created in 1957 was incorporated in AID and AID was made responsible for foreign economic assistance and the coordination of military assistance.
The administration of the foreign aid program was largely reorganized at the time of the establishment of AID. The responsibility for operations was shifted from functional offices to geographic offices. Four regional offices representing Latin America, Europe and Africa, the Near East and South Asia, and the Far East were established with each having an assistant administrator responsible to the Administrator of AID. The effect of reorganization has been to plan aid on a country by country basis rather than project by project as was formerly done.
The working concepts that are the basis for the operations of AID are:
1. Long-term development assistance based on well-conceived program plans prepared by the developing countries in cooperation with the United States will result in significant progress toward self-sustaining growth during the 1960's.
2. Assistance will be successful in relation to the ability and willingness of developing countries to help themselves.
3. Aid programs will be tailored to the capacity of a country to use assistance effectively, as well as to the varied needs of different countries with respect to the threat of Communism. The nature of the aid to be used will depend on the situation in the particular country.
4. In order to encourage self-help, loans on reasonable terms are preferable to grants for long-term development and repayment should be in dollars rather than local currency.
5. Assistance to the less-developed countries is the collective responsibility of the developed countries and a greater share of the responsibility for aid should be borne by our allies.
U. S. Agency for International Development
The function of the International Training Division is to prepare cooperating country nationals to perform important roles in their nations' development programs. The participant training program's objectives are to improve the technical, professional, and managerial skills and knowledge of participants, and to introduce attitudes and values essential to social and economic development. AID is responsible for training approximately 6,500 persons annually in the U.S., plus 2,200 abroad. Each training program is designed by AID's International Training Division to meet the needs of a specific country or project within that country.
The Division regularly makes use of numerous other government agencies in carrying out its training functions. These agencies make available their technical knowledge and facilities to the appropriate training programs.
This collection consists of the program and itinerary for each of the various AID sponsored training programs carried out in the U.S. and other countries. The training programs are arranged under the Bureaus which sponsored them and include such diverse fields as agriculture, labor, industry and mining, transportation, public health, housing, public administration, community development, public safety and many others.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Economic development.; Economic assistance, American.; Economic assistance -- International cooperation; United States. Agency for International Development
5622229
- Series I: Information About AID
  - Information About Agency for International Development, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains 13 booklets on the Agency for International Development
    - The General Electric Forum for National Security and Free World Progress, Volume VI, Number 4, 1963-10-1963-12
    - AID...in summary, 1966
    - The AID Program, 1964-06
    - Alliance for Progress...and American Partnership, 1963-08
    - Personnel Administration and Operations of Agency for International Development: Report of Senator Gale W. McGee to the Committee on Appropriations, 1963-11-29
    - Third Anniversary of the Alliance for Progress, President Lyndon B. Johnson, 1964
    - Training for Development, Third Edition, 1963
      Two copies.
    - The AID Participant Training Program - How it Works, 1962-06
    - Report to the congress on the Foreign Assistance Program for Fiscal Year 1962, 1963
    - Training for Development, Second Edition, 1962
    - The Alliance for Progress...an American Partnership, 1965-12
    - Food for Peace...Building a Better World, 1963-03
    - Quiet Warriors: Supporting Social Revolution in Viet-Nam, 1966
    - AID Discussion Paper No. 12: Measures to Ensure Effective Use of AID by Joan M. Nelson and Gustav Ranis, 1966-09
  - Information About the Agency for International Development, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains 12 booklets on international aid
    - Message on Free World Defense and Assistance Programs by John F. Kennedy, April 2, 1963
    - ...the hand and the heart of this country... by Lyndon B. Johnson, 1964
    - The Alliance Reaches a Turning Point by Lyndon B. Johnson, 1964
    - AID's Technical Assistance Program: the Point 4 Program of the Sixties, 1964
    - Managements Improvements in the AID Program, 1964
    - Training for Leadership and Service, June 25-26, 1962
    - The Foreign Aid Program Today: Answers to Four Basic Questions by David E. Bell, 1963
    - Foreign Aid and U.S. National Security by David E. Bell, 1963
    - Foreign Aid...Controversy and Reality by Frank M. Coffin, 1963
    - Developing Cooperatives Overseas: New Directions, 1964
    - A Two-Way Street: Benefits Accruing from the International Training Programs of A.I.D., 1963
    - Proposed Mutual Defense and Assistance Programs FY 1964, 1963
  - Program and Itinerary, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Latin-American Trade Union Training Group XVIII, International Cooperation Administration
  - Los Companeros, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Partners of the Alliance News, March 1966
  - A Hand, not a Handout, July 12, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Partners of Alliance program in US and Latin America
  - Press Releases: February 1 through February 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases: March 15 through March 21, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Partners of the Alliance: The Grassroots Approach, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    2 booklets
  - Partners of the Alliance: Basic Proceedings, First Inter-American Conference, 1965-06-10-1965-06-11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series II: Bureau for Far East
  Contains programs and itineraries for visits from representatives of Public International Organizations (PIO) to the US.
  - Indonesia: General Participant Training "Price Statistics," PIO/P 497-11-990-179-1-40310, 1964-08-27-1965-08-27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Part II
  - Vietnam Industrial Relations Development Team, PIO/P 430-326-1-70416, 1967-08-21-1967-10-21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - China: Business Accounting Observation Team, Project No. 484-80012, 1968-05-28-1968-07-19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Thailand Community Development: High Level Administration, Training and Field Operation, Project 493-80625, 1968-05-14-1968-06-20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Thailand: Training in Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 493-124-1-50143, 1965-12-29-1966-09-10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vietnam: PIO/P 430-327-1-70439, 1967-06-22-1967-08-15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Thailand: PIO/P 493-11-195-1-80504, 1967-10-12-1968-04-20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thailand: Manpower and Educational Development Planning, PIO/P 493-11-690-142-1-60583, PIO/P 493-11-690-142-1-60584, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Vietnam: PIO/P 430-301-1-60280, 1966-06-16-1966-08-10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Professor and Head of the Research and Documentation Division National Institute Administration Saigon, Vietnam
  - Philippines: Financial Management Impact Team, PIO/P 492-60132, 1967-01-20-1967-02-26 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Republic of China, India, Japan, Republic of Korea, Nepal, Pakistan, the Philippines, Thailand: Asian Productivity Organization: Food Industry Study Team, 498-30006, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - China, Honduras, Nicaragua, Peru, Philippines, Trinidad, Turkey, Vietnam: Industrial Development and Management Studies, The Formation and Flow of Capital, Projects 915-39157 and 910-40089, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Republic of China: Paints and Resins Productivity Study Team, Project 484-30111, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - China: Industrial Investment Promotion Productivity Council, Project 484-30124, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - China: Public Administration and Manpower Improvement, PIO/P 484-Q-72-AA-I-30057/40021, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - China: Pulp and Paper Productivity Study Team, Project 484-30125, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - China: Labor Administration Productivity Team, PIO/P 484-J-27-AB-20161, 1962-09-21-1962-11-16 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Republic of China: Labor's Role in Productivity, PIO/P 484-J-27-AB-I-20191, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Korea: Metals Industry Study Team, Project 489-20092, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Korea: Korean Manpower Team, Project 489-60104, 1965-03-20-1966-04-15 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Korea: Industrial Development Study Team, Project 489-60028, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Philippines: Industrial Chemistry Team, Project 492-20038, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Philippines: Industrial Real Estate Team, Project 492-20160, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Philippines: Shoe Manufacturing Team, Project 492-30072, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Philippines: Pharmaceutical Productivity Team, Project 492-30073, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Republic of the Philippines: Development Bankers' Productivity Team, Project 492-30141, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Philippines: Public Administration Improvement, PIO/P 492-Q-79-AA-1-30191, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Philippines: Manpower Development and Utilization, PIO/P 492-U-45-AA-1-20051, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Indonesia: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 497-N-41-AC-1-30380, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Indonesia: Labor Inspection and Statistics, PIO/P 497-N-41-AC-1-30372, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Indonesia: Social Security Training Program, PIO/P 497-AB-72-AA-5-1-30113, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Indonesia: Programs and Itineraries (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Labor Leadership Training, PIO/P 497-N41-AC-1-20227, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Employment Service, PIO/P 497-AC-41-AE-5-1-30385, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Department of Labor Employment Service, PIO/P 497-N41-AC-1-20240, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Labor Safety Inspection Training, PIO/P 497-N41-AC-1-20251, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Labor leadership Training, PIO/P 497-N-41-AC-1-20264, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Labor Leadership Training, PIO/P N-41-AC-1-30371, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Employment Security, PIO/P 497-41-093-1-05200, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Labor Leadership Training, PIO/P 497-N-41-AC-1-30371, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Executive Leadership Study Team, Project 497-40092, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: PIO/P 497-093-1-40084, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Indonesia: Labor Leadership Statistics, PIO/P 497-N-41-AC-1-30020, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Vietnam: Programs and Itineraries, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Vietnam: Labor Institutions, PIO/P 430-AC-83-AF-1-30129, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Vietnam: Labor Institutions Team, PIO/P 430-50338, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Vietnam: 2nd Industry Productivity Study Team, Project 430-50248, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Vietnam: Industry Productivity Study Team, Project 430-40016, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Vietnam: Labor Institutions, PIO/P 430-222-1-40133, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Department of Labor International Technical Assistance Corps (DOLITAC) Staff Papers (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 10: Edgar C. McVoy Mission to Thailand, 1965-11-06-1965-12-21 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 13: Richard B. Zoeckler Mission to Vietnam, 1966-03-19-1966-06-02 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 16: Adrian Roberts Mission to the Republic of China, 1965-07-26-1965-08-20 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 23: George L. Jackson Mission to Ryukyu Islands, 1966-06-23-1966-10-01 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 39: Matilda R. Sugg Mission to Republic of China, 1967-02-1967-03 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 45: Chester W Helper Mission to Republic of China, 1964-11-1967-07 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 46: Harry Weiss Mission to Republic of China, 1963-12 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 47: Edgar C. McVoy Mission to Korea, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Vietnam: Nguyen van Tung, PIO/P 430-222-1-40495, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Vietnam: Farmers Trade Union Team, PIO/P 430-222-1-60460, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Vietnam: Ministry of Labor team, Project 430-70107, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Vietnam: Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 430-222-1-40495, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Vietnam: Trade Union Cooperative and Credit Union Team, PIO/P 430-326-1-70417, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series III. Bureau for Near East and South Asia
  - Iran: Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 265-131-1-50081, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Iran: Social Security Training Program, PIO/P 265-R-77-AA-1-30147, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Multi-Country Industry Orientation Study Team, Project SP-100, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Afghanistan, Brazil, Congo, Costa Rica, Ethiopia, Iraq, Indonesia, Liberia, Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Togo, Turkey, Vietnam, Zanzibar
  - Cyprus: Trade Union Team, Labor Training Division, PIO/P 233-U-41-AA-1-20005, PIO/P 233-U-41-AA-1-20007, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Greece, Peru, Philippines: Productivity and Employment Study, Program No. 3 - Group III, Project 915-39153, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Greece: Management Association Study, Project 240-20010, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - India: Programs and Itineraries (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Trade Union Development and Worker's Education Training, Employment Market Information, Tools Jigs and Fixtures Productivity Team, Instruments Industry Productivity Team, Labor and Price Statistics, Collection of Employment Market Information Project, Rol
    - India: Trade Union Development, Workers' Education Training, PIO/P 386-15-410-109-1-40179, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - India: Employment Market Information, PIO/P 386-11-450-161-1-40150, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - India: Tools, Jigs and Fixtures Productivity Team, Project 386-20170, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - India: Instruments Industry Productivity Team, Project 386-30237, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - India: Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 386-45-161-20011, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - India: Collection of Employment Market Information Project, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-30053, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - India: Role of Labor in Productivity Team, PIO/P 386-15-270-115-1-40191, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - India: Programs and Itineraries (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Occupational Research and Analysis Project, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-30052, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Placement of Scientific and Technical Personnel Project, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-30055, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Chemical Fertilizer Industry Study Team, Project 386-49154, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Industrial Relations, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Industrial Relations, PIO/P 386-J-27-AA-1-20157, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Industrial Relations, PIO/P 386-J-27-AA-1-20161, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - India: Industrial Safety and Hygiene, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-30059, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - India: Programs and Itineraries (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Industrial Safety and Hygiene, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-30057, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: National Productivity Council, PIO/P 386-J-27-AA-1-20165, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Labor Ministry Training, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-20088, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Labor Ministry Training, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-20090, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Personnel Management and Industrial Relations, PIO/P 386-15-270-115-1-40166, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Mining Safety, PIO/P 386-11-450-161-1-40145, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Labor Ministry Training - Collection of Employment, PIO/P 386-U-49-AB-1-20136, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - India: Placement of Physically Handicapped Personnel Project, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Programs and Itineraries, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Nepal: Industrial Observation Team, Project 367-20215, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Thailand: Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 493-124-1-40127, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Vietnam: Labor Institutions Team, PIO/P 540-222-1-70036, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - India: National Productivity Council, PIO/P 386-15-270-115-1-40344, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Korea: Suk Choon Yoon, PIO/9 489-13-230-606-1-40064, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Turkey: Industrial Health and Safety Team, PIO/P 277-356-1-60059, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - India: T.V. Swaminathan and R. Sampath Kumaran, PIO/P 386-161-1-60361, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Indonesia: Mr. Soerjanatakoesoema, PIO/P 497-11-990-183-1-80017, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Thailand: Training in Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 493-142-1-70569, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Pakistan: Nisar A. S. Mian, Muhammad A. Azim, Nayeemul Hasan, PIO/P 391-245-1-50526, PIO/P 391-245-1-50527, PIO/P 391-245-1-50528, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Thailand: Training in Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 493-124-1-70855, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - India: Labor Law Administration Team, PIO/P 386-161-1-70209, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Department of Labor International Technical Assistance Corps (DOLITAC) Staff Papers, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 28: Eugene Vinogradoff Mission to Pakistan, 1964-11-1966-06 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 41: Adrian Roberts Mission to Pakistan, 1964-07 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Staff Paper No. 49: Forest L. Miller Mission to Turkey, 1967-04-1967-07 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - India: Employment Services Team, PIO/P 386-161-1-70306, 1967-09-07-1967-11-17 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Trade Union Development, Worker's Education Training, PIO/P 386-109-1-60250, 1966-09-15-1967-03-11 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - India: Industrial Relations Training (Worker Education Team), PIO/P 386-109-1-70206, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Turkey: Programs and Itineraries (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, Industrial Health & Safety, PIO/P 277-356-1-60095, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-J-41-AE-1-20220, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Turkey: Executive Administration Training, PIO/P 277-Q-49-AD-1-30134, PIO/P-277-Q-49-AD-1-30135, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Group A
    - Turkey: Executive Administration Training, PIO/P 277-Q-49-AD-1-30134, PIO/P-277-Q-49-AD-1-30135, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Group B
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training Team, PIO/P 277-356-1-40287, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Turkey: Programs and Itineraries (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Turkey: Executive Administrative Training, Group C, PIO/P 277-Q-49-AD-1-30134, 277-Q-49-AD-1-30135, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Turkey: Executive Administration Training, PIO/P 277-Q-49-AD-1-30225, 277-Q-49-AD-1-30195, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Turkey: Manpower Planning and Programming, PIO/P 277-R-46-AJ-I-30136, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Turkey: Workers' Education (I), Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-356-1-60144, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, Women's Role in Trade Union Movement, PIO/P 277-356-1-60194, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training in the Food Processing and Agriculturally Allied Industries, PIO/P 277-356-1-60159, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Turkey: Programs and Itineraries (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training (Trade Union Journalism and Communication), PIO/P 277-356-1-60184, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Manpower Planning and Programming, PIO/P 277-R-46-AJ-1-30137, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, Structure, Function and Administration of National Unions (Internal Organizations), PIO/P 277-356-1-60114, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Industrial Health and Safety Team, PIO/P 277-356-1-70082, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Contract Negotiations and Research Team, PIO/P 277-356-1-70163, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Trade Union Cooperatives Team, PIO/P 277-356-1-70127, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turkey: Labor and Price Statistics, PIO/P 277-Q-49-AD-1-30322, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Turkey: Programs and Itineraries (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Manpower Planning and Programming, PIO/P 277-11-460-363-1-40188, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-13-410-356-1-40312, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Workers Education Team No. 4, PIO/P 277-356-1-50252, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Pulp and Paper Productivity Study Team, Project 277-30179, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Beet Sugar Industry Study Team, Project 277-30180, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Rubber Products Processing and Manufacture Study Team, Project 277-30181, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-13-410-356-1-40258, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Turkey: Programs and Itineraries (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-13-410-356-1-40243, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Manpower Planning and Programming, PIO/P 277-11-460-363-1-40211, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-356-1-40320, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-13-410-356-1-40205, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Training, PIO/P 277-13-410-356-1-40253, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Industrial Relations Study, PIO/P 277-40297, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Turkey: Fruit and Vegetable Processing and Canning Study Team, Project 277-30182, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)